Hello and welcome back.
In this quick demo, I want to map the things we covered in the previous lecture to a real
world example.
To be specific, the problem that the MCP is trying to solve.
Here I have a closed desktop installed, and if I ask the model to summarize a document
for me that is saved on my Google Drive in one paragraph, and then it translate that document
into German, let's give that a quick try.
Now obviously this is not going to work, it says I do not have access to Google Drive
or other internal tools to search for the document in your Google Drive.
So without an MCP server, I have to log in into my Google Drive account, find that document,
copy the content of that document, paste it into this chat, and then write the prompt.
Having an MCP server is going to do all of this work for me.
I have already authorized my cloud to access my Google Drive.
So at this point all what I have to do is to enable Google Drive MCP server integration.
So I'm going in here and then just enable Drive Search.
Now if I just copy paste the same prompt and then try it one more time and let's see what's
going to happen.
So it looks like the model was able to find that document.
And right now it's writing a summary in one paragraph and then we can immediately see
the German translation.
So to quickly summarize what happened behind the scene, cloud was able to invoke or call
an MCP server on Google Drive and it was authorized to access my file.
And then the MCP server was able to read that file, get the content, send it back to
the cloud and then at this point, since the cloud was able to access the content of that
document, it was able to summarize it and translate that for me.
I hope that this quick demo has been informative for you and help you to map the theory
to a real example.
Thanks for watching and I will see you in the next lecture.